Cuong Pham

≥ cuongquocpham151@gmail.com | **𝚱** cqpham28.github.io | **in** cuongpham281 | **ፍ** cqpham28

PROFESSIONAL INTERESTS

I have a strong interest in data-driven techniques incorporating signal processing and machine learning methods for healthcare research with the goal of enhancing the digitalization of the computer-aid medical system. I conduct human-based biosignal experiments and analyze multi-modal biomedical datasets associated to different sub-domain studies in neurology, cardiology, and digital remote monitoring.

EDUCATION

Ritsumeikan University

Shiga, Japan

M.Eng. in Advanced Information Science and Engineering

2021 - 2023

• Fully-funded MEXT Scholarship by Japanese Government

VNU-HCM University of Technology

HCMC, Vietnam

B.Eng. in Physics Engineering

2015 - 2020

- Biomedical Engineering specialization
- 1st-rank Faculty Honors (2016) | GPA: 3.5/4.0

WORK EXPERIENCE

VinUni-Illinois Smart Health Center, VinUniversity

Hanoi, Vietnam

PhD Candidate (Advisor: Dr. Hieu Pham)

Aug 2024 - now

• Mental Health Research: Research Coordinator for a team of 10 multidisciplinary experts and graduate students; collaborating with multiple hospitals & clinics in Vietnam for a large-scale digital-phenotying cohorts; developing a Cloud-based platform for seamless wearable data acquisition and retrieval.

School of Biomedical Engineering, VNU-HCM International University

HCMC, Vietnam

Research Assistant (Advisor: Dr. Huong Ha)

Nov 2023 - Jul 2024

- Brain Computer Interface (BCI) Research: designed and calibrated experiment protocol; supported data acquisition and management process; taught EEG signal processing for undergrad students.
- Data Modeling: serialized and processed the collected in-house datasets; developed ML pipeline for predictive modeling tasks; conducted performance benchmarking with other data sources; deployed and maintained web apps for Cloud storage, performance response analysis and data visualization.
- Online-BCI: collaborated with the software developers to build a customized desktop app for BCI data acquisition and response controller; deployed and evaluated user-specific calibrated modeling for real-time mouse control system; conducted inspection process to integrate the platform into cross-regional collaborative project (KC4.0-MOST).

HATO Medical Technologies ApS

Odense, Denmark

Machine Learning Engineer

Jun 2022 - Nov 2023

- Cardiology Research: worked closely with cardiologists and health-tech startup stakeholders to establish standardized clinical labeling protocols tailored to specific use cases at a local Danish emergency department focusing on final outcomes for cardiovascular diseases; conducted literature reviews for evidence-based decision making, wrote technical documentation, prepared research materials and wrote grant proposals/fundings.
- Data Pipeline: collected and handled data from public repositories and clinical sources. Implemented a scalable data processing pipeline, including data cleaning, and alignment across sources. Collaborated with software developers to integrate a data serialization pipeline into the backend architecture of the in-house product.
- AI/ML Development: implemented a Cloud-based internal data management system with interactive web app and tested its streamline workflow. Monitored and evaluated time-series predictive modeling; deployed models for real-time abnormalities detection and interpretation; inspected and ensured the solution meet technical requirements.

M.Eng Research Assitant (Advisor: Dr. Kashihara Koji)

Oct 2021 - Aug 2023

- Drug Infusion Research: developed a hybrid controller to regulate cardiac output and mean arterial pressure within during drug infusion using ML model with short-time previous drug inputs; evaluated on a mathematical modeling responses of dogs with heart-failure dataset.
- RPPG Signal Quality Enhancement: designed pipeline to track landmarks on customized forehead region-of-interest, using combination of unsupervised optical models and deep auto-encoder network to improve signal-to-noise ratio; evaluated on public remote-photoplethysmograph datasets.
- RPPG Experiments: collected data (5 healthy subjects with different camera settings & postures); designed platform to synchronize facial video and blood volume pulse signal; evaluated heart rate benchmarks among different configurations with unsupervised methods and statistical analysis.
- RPPG Feature Assessment: investigated the reliability of waveform feature related to cardiac aging/stiffness by using a real-time Face-Mesh tracking with deep learning model and a customized morphology extraction; evaluated on a public well controlled rPPG dataset.
- Thesis: "Remote Photoplethysmography Assessment Using Deep Learning (Committee Chair: Dr. Ruck Thawonmas).

GTOPIA Vietnam. Ltd

HCMC, Vietnam

Signal Processing Intern (Advisor: Dr. Liem Huynh)

Jan - Jun 2020

- Wearable Research: designed pipeline with API for raw data aggregation from in-house wearable product; designed signal processing pipeline for vital-sign hemodynamic monitoring; conducted experiments on commercial wristbands's performance under different usage scenarios.
- Data Collection: collaborated with Ho-Chi-Minh-Heart-Institute for large-scale clinical data acquisition. Processed, categorized, and digitalized health records of administered patients with cardiovascular diseases.

Biomedical Electronics Laboratory, Shibaura Institute of Technology

Tokyo, Japan

Research Intern (Advisor: Dr. Shinichiro Kanoh)

Sep - Nov 2019

• **EEG Experiment**: involved in data collection activities for Auditory and Motor Imagery studies; conducted experimental analysis on EEG visualization for motor cortex response and how to conduct neuro-feedback. Revised experiment procedure for the Bachelor Thesis.

PUBLICATION

Peer-reviewed Conference Paper

- C. Pham and K. Kashihara (2022, March), A Hybrid Controller for Multiple Drug Infusion in Heart Failure using Convolutional Neural Network. In 2022 IEEE 4th Global Conference on Life Sciences and Technologies (LifeTech) (pp. 340-344). [paper]
- Nguyen, M. T. D., **Pham, C. Q.**, Nguyen, H. N., Le, K. Q., & Huynh, L. Q. (2022), A Statistical Approach to Evaluate Beta Response in Motor Imagery-Based Brain-Computer Interface. 8th International Conference on the Development of Biomedical Engineering in Vietnam (pp. 203-217). [paper]

TALKS

- [Dec 2024] Development and Evaluation of Multimodal AI Framework for Mental Health Assessment: A Preliminary Study @ Brain Informatics 2024 (Bangkok, Thailand).
- [Jun 2024] Evaluation of Cue-based Protocol Implementations in Motor Imagery based Brain-Computer Interface Experiments @ NeuroCoB 2024 (Putrajaya, Malaysia).
- [Oct 2019] Exercise Physiology: Improving Stationary Bike Training Performance Using Heart Rate Variability @ ISAS 2019, (HCMC, Vietnam).
- [Oct 2019] Research into the relationship between cardiac responses and neural activity to improve classification of EEG-based imaginary action @ iCAEP 6 (Thai Nguyen, Vietnam).
- [Mar 2019] Exercise Physiology: Cardiac Endurance Training for Students by Stationary Bike @ <u>SEATUC 2019</u> (Hanoi, Vietnam)

ACADEMIC ACTIVITIES

Graduate Teaching Assistant

- [Fall 2024] COMP3040 Computer Vision @ CECS, VinUniversity
- [Fall 2022] Experiments in Artificial and Natural Intelligence @ CISE, Ritsumeikan University

School Projects

- [Sep 2022 Jan 2023] WasteWise @ GSISE, Ritsumeikan University
 - Team of 6 collaborate with TH Nürnberg (Germany); develop an AI-based mobile app for trash-bins time collection recommendation in public spaces using crowdsourcing dataset.
 - Results are evaluated on the pilot data in Shiga and Kyoto city.
- [Aug 2022] Pic2Fit @ KYOTO Design Lab, Kyoto Institute of Technology
 - Design a proof-of-concept virtual clothes fitting application tailored for small shops in Kyoto, Japan.
 - Awarded 2nd prize in Kyoto Startup Weekend Competition; by Techstars.
- [Sep 2018 Mar 2019] Stationary Bike @ VNU-HCM University of Technology
 - Designed circuits for workload adjustment adapting to the biker's heart rate; collaborated with HCMC Institute of Biomedical Physics to evaluated VO2max improvement on students over endurance training course.
 - Presented results at ISAS 2019 conference; system are intergrated into laboratory experiment course.
- [Mar Jun 2017] Pet Feeder
 - Tech-lead freelance team to design the low-cost automated pet-feeding system; conducted mechanical design and material 3D-printing, developed electrical circuits and platform for IoT user control.
 - **Delivered** MVP to the reserved customers.

Community Involvement

- [Dec 2024] Conference Technical Staff @ ACML 2024.
- [Jan Feb 2023] English Teaching Staff @ Ritsumeikan Juniodr High.
- [Oct 2022] Conference Technical Staff @ IEEE/RSJ IROS 2022.
- [Sep 2020 Apr 2021] Host EEG Research Seminar @ VNU-HCM University of Technology.

Mentoring Students

- Tuong Nguyen H., now Research Staff @ VNU-HCM International University (VN).
- Hidetake Kondo, now Software Developer @ e-Jan Networks Co. (JP).
- Ha Nguyen L. N., now Biomedical Engineer @ Cho Ray Hospital (VN).

SELECTED SKILLS

- Programming: Python, MATLAB, Linux, R, SQL, Javascript, C#
- Machine Learning: OpenCV, Scikit-learn, LightGBM, XGBoost, Keras, Pytorch, Lightning
- Tech Stacks: Database (MySQL, MongoDB, Firebase), Webapp (Streamlit, Flask), Mobile (React Native), Cloud AWS (S3, EC2, Lambda), Tools (Git, Docker, Jira)
- Miscellaneous: Data Analysis (scipy, pandas, ggplot2, dplyr), Bio-Signal Experimentation (ECG, EEG, PPG, wearable/bio-sensors), Signal Processing (spectral & time-frequency analysis, transformation [SVD, PCA, ICA], filtering IIR/FIR), Circuit (ESP32, Arduino, Raspberry Pi, IoT sensors)
- Language: Vietnamese (native), English (fluent)

REFERENCE

Hieu Pham, Ph.D.

Assistant Professor, College of Engineering & Computer Science (CECS) &

Scientific Director, Entrepreneurship Lab (E-lab),

PI at VinUni-Illinois Smart Health Center, VinUniversity.

Email: hieu.ph@vinuni.edu.vn

Ha Thi Thanh Huong, Ph.D.

Head of Brain Health Lab &

Chair, Department of Tissue Engineering and Regenerative Medicine

School of Biomedical Engineering, International University

Vietnam National University in Ho Chi Minh city.

Email: htthuong@hcmiu.edu.vn

Stefan K. Johansen

COO, HATO Medical Technologies,

Partners & Board Members, Black Capital Ventures.

Email: skj@hatomedicaltechnologies.com